[
    {
        "question": "  Let us consider  the algorithm  magic(x) , where x is a natural number (1 ≤ x ≤ 32000). Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "For any input value x strictly less than 10 the algorithm  returns False ."
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm  decomposes the number  x into its  prime factors ."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm  returns True  if the number  x is a perfect square ."
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm  does not return True for any valid value of input parameter x."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm magic(x):\n    st ← 1\n    dr ← x\n    While st ≤ dr execute\n        mj ← (st + dr) DIV 2\n        If mj * mj = x then\n            return True\n        EndIf\n        If mj * mj < x then\n            st ← mj + 1\n        else\n            dr ← mj – 1\n        EndIf\n    EndWhile\n    return False\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "C",
        "index": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "  Let us consider the algorithm calculeaza(a,b) , where a and b are natural numbers (1 ≤ a, b ≤ 10000). Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "If a = 107 and b = 101, the algorithm returns the value 107."
            },
            {
                "B": "If a = 1001 and b  = 101, the algorithm returns the value 1001."
            },
            {
                "C": "For all algorithm calls with 1 ≤ a ≤ 10000 and b = 101, the returned value is equal to a."
            },
            {
                "D": "For all algorithm calls with a = 1001 and 1 ≤ b ≤ 10000, the returned value is equal to 1001."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm calculeaza (a, b):\nx ← 1\nFor i ← 1, b execute\nx ← (x MOD 10) * a\nEndFor\nreturn x\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "ABD",
        "index": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm afis(n) , where n is a natural number (0 ≤  n ≤  10000). Which of the following statements are true for the call afis(n) ? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm prints an array of numbers in which the first element is equal to the last element, the\nsecond element is equal to the second to last element, etc  (except for the middle elemen t)."
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm prints an array of even numbers."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm prints an array of numbers in ascending order followed by numbers in descending\norder."
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm prints an array of numbers in descending order followed by numbers in ascending\norder."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm afis(n):\n    Write n, \" \"\n    If n > 0 then\n        afis(n DIV 2)\n        Write n, \", \"\n    EndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "AD",
        "index": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm cauta(n, b), where n and b are natural number s (0 ≤ n ≤ 106, 2 ≤ b < 10). Which of the fol lowing statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm computes and returns the number of digits of n."
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm returns 1 if the number n is a power of b and 0 otherwise."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm computes and returns the number of digits equal to 0 from the representation in\nbase b of number n."
            },
            {
                "D": "The a lgorithm returns 1 if number n ends in digit b and 0 otherwise."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm cauta(n, b):\nv ← 0\nIf n = 0 then\nreturn 1\nelse\nm ← n\nWhile m > 0 execute\nIf m MOD b = 0 then\nv ← v + 1\nEndIf\nm ← m DIV b\nEndWhile\nreturn v\nEndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "C",
        "index": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider  the algorithm  abc(a, n, p) , where n is a natural number (1 ≤ n ≤ 10000), p is an integer number (-10000 ≤ p ≤ 10000), and a is an array of  n non-zero natural numbers  (a[1], a[2], …, a[n]). Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm  returns 0 if and only if p is a negative number or is greater than n."
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm  returns  the element on position p if p is strictly greater than 0 and less than or\nequal to the length of the array ."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm  never returns  0 for parameter values that meet the given preconditions ."
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm  returns  the element at position p if p is greater than or equal to 0 and strictly less\nthan the length of the array ."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm abc(a, n, p):\n    If n < 1 then\n        return -1\n    else\n        If (1 ≤ p) AND (p ≤ n) then\n            return a[p]\n        else\n            return 0\n        EndIf\n    EndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "B",
        "index": 5
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to generate al the numbers with n digits composed  only of digits 0, 6, 7,  there is an algorithm which, for  n = 2, generates in ascending order the numbers 60, 66, 67, 70, 76, 77. If n = 4 and the same algorithm is used, what is the number generated immediately after the number 6767? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "7667"
            },
            {
                "B": "6760"
            },
            {
                "C": "6776"
            },
            {
                "D": "None of the other variants are correct ."
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "D",
        "index": 6
    },
    {
        "question": "For a natural number nr (1000 ≤ nr ≤ 1000000), we define the decrement operation as follows: if the last digit of nr is not 0, we subtract 1 from nr, otherwise, we divide nr by 10 and we keep the integer part of the quotient. Which of the following algorithms,  for the call  decrementare(nr, k) ,  return the number obtained by applying the decrement operation k times (0 ≤ k ≤ 100) on the number nr? For example, for nr = 15243 and k = 10, the result will be 151. ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "Algorithm decrementare(nr, k):\nIf k = 0 then\nreturn nr\nelse\nIf nr MOD 10 ≠ 0 then\nreturn decrementare(nr - 1, k - 1)\nElse\nreturn decrementare(nr DIV 10, k - 1)\nEndIf\nEndIf\nEndAlgorithm"
            },
            {
                "B": "Algorithm decrementare(nr, k):\n    While k > 0 execute\n        If nr MOD 10 = 0 then\n            nr ← nr DIV 10\n        else\n            nr ← nr - 1\n        EndIf\n  k ← k - 1\n    EndWhile\n    return nr\nEndAlgorithm"
            },
            {
                "C": "Algorithm decrementare(nr, k):\nFor i ← 1, k execute\nIf nr MOD 10 > 0 then\nnr ← nr DIV 10\nelse\nnr ← nr - 1\nEndIf\nEndFor\nreturn nr\nEndAlgorithm"
            },
            {
                "D": "Algorithm decrementare(nr, k):\n    If k = 0 then\n        return nr\n    else\n        If k > nr MOD 10 then\n            nr1 ← nr DIV 10\n            return decrementare(nr1,   k - nr MOD 10 - 1)\n        else\n            return decrementare(nr - k, 0)\n        EndIf\n    EndIf\nEndAlgorithm"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "ABD",
        "index": 7
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the  algorithm fn with the following parameter specification: an array v with n natural numbers ( v[1], v[2], …, v[n]) and the integer number n (1 ≤ n ≤ 10000). Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm returns the number of odd elements from vector v."
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm returns the number of elements from vector v that are powers of 2."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm returns the number of elements from vector  v that contain only even digits."
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm returns the number of  elements  from  vector  v that contain only odd digi ts."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm fn(v, n):\na ← 0\nFor i ← 1, n execute\nok ← True\nb ← v[i]\nWhile (b ≠ 0) AND (ok = True) execute\nIf b MOD 2 = 1 then\nok ← False\nEndIf\nb ← b DIV 10\nEndWhile\nIf ok = True then\na ← a + 1\nEndIf\nEndFor\nreturn a\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "C",
        "index": 8
    },
    {
        "question": "  The algorithm  magic(s, n) has as input parameters an array s of n characters ( s[1], s[2], …, s[n]) and the integer number n (1 ≤ n ≤ 10000). Which of the following statements are true?   ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm returns 1 if s has an even number of characters."
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm returns 1 if s is a palindrome."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm contains an error since the expression n – i + 1 can have negative values during\nexecution."
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm returns 1  if s contains only alphanumeric characters."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm magic(s, n):\n    i ← n\n    While 1 ≤ i execute\n        If s[i] ≠ s[n - i + 1] then\n            return 0\n        EndIf\n        i ← i - 1\n    EndWhile\n    return 1\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "B",
        "index": 9
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the following sequence of pseudocode statements : Read a For i ← 1, a - 1 execute     For j ← i + 2, a execute         If i + j > a - 1 then             Write a, \" \", i, \" \", j             Write new line         EndIf     EndFor EndFor How many pairs of solutions will be printed after executing the pseudocode sequence for a = 9? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "13"
            },
            {
                "B": "15"
            },
            {
                "C": "19"
            },
            {
                "D": "None of the other variants are correct ."
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "C",
        "index": 10
    },
    {
        "question": " The a lgorit hm ceFace(n)  has as input parameter  a natural number  n (0 ≤ n ≤ 10000). What is the value returned by the call  ceFace(9876) ? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "16"
            },
            {
                "B": "48"
            },
            {
                "C": "14"
            },
            {
                "D": "63"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm ceFace(n):\ns ← 0\nWhile n > 0 execute\nc ← n MOD 10\nIf c MOD 2 = 0 then\ns ← s + c\nEndIf\nn ← n DIV 10\nEndWhile\nreturn s\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "C",
        "index": 11
    },
    {
        "question": "The algorithm generare(n)  processes a natural number n (0 < n < 100). Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "If n = 10, the algorithm returns 2."
            },
            {
                "B": "If n = 10, the algorithm returns 1."
            },
            {
                "C": "If n = 3, the algorithm returns 4."
            },
            {
                "D": "The two calls generare(3)  and generare(30)  will return the same value."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm generare(n):\n    nr ← 0\n    For i ← 1, 1801 execute\n        used[i] ← False\n    EndFor\n    While not  used[n] execute\n        sum ← 0\n        used[n] ← True\n        While n ≠ 0 execute\n            digit ← n MOD 10\n            n ← n DIV 10\n            sum ← sum + digit * digit * digit\n        EndWhile\n        n ← sum\n        nr ← nr + 1\n    EndWhile\n    return nr\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "ACD",
        "index": 12
    },
    {
        "question": "The algorithm f(a, b) has as input parameter s two natural number s a and b (1 ≤ a < b ≤ 100 0): Unfortunately, the algorithm calls itself recursively an infinite number of times. State what will be the value of b when variable a becomes 0  for the first time . The algorithm is called using the instruction: c ← f(20, 10) ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "100"
            },
            {
                "B": "160"
            },
            {
                "C": "320"
            },
            {
                "D": "640"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm f(a, b):\nIf a > 0 then\nreturn b + f(a DIV 2, b * 2)\nEndIf\nreturn b + f(a * 2, b DIV 2)\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "C",
        "index": 13
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following expressions have the value true if and only if the natural number n is divisible by 3 and has the last digit 4 or 6: ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "(n MOD 3 = 0) OR ((n MOD 10 = 4) AND (n MOD 10 = 6))"
            },
            {
                "B": "(n MOD 6 = 0) AND ((n MOD 10 = 4) OR (n MOD 10 = 6))"
            },
            {
                "C": "((n MOD 9 = 0) AND (n MOD 10 = 4)) OR ((n MOD 3 = 0) AND (n MOD 10 = 6))"
            },
            {
                "D": "(n MOD 3 = 0) AND (((n MOD 2 = 0) AND (n MOD 5 = 0)) OR ((n MOD 2 = 0) AND (n MOD 5 = 1)))"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "B",
        "index": 14
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the following logical expression  (X OR Z) AND (X OR Y). Choose the values for X, Y, Z such that the evaluation of the expression gives the result True: ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "X ← False; Y ← False; Z ← True;"
            },
            {
                "B": "X ← True; Y ← False; Z ← False;"
            },
            {
                "C": "X ← False; Y ← True; Z ← False;"
            },
            {
                "D": "X ← True; Y ← True; Z ← True;"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "BD",
        "index": 15
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider all strings of length l ϵ {1, 2, 3} consisting of letters in the set { a, b, c, d, e}. How many of these strings have elements ordered  in strictly ascending  order  and also having an odd number of consonants? ( b, c and d are consonants) ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "14"
            },
            {
                "B": "13"
            },
            {
                "C": "26"
            },
            {
                "D": "81"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "B",
        "index": 16
    },
    {
        "question": " In order to display a square together with  its diagonals, we will use the characters * (asterisk) and . (dot) (for the space inside the square except the diagonals). The following example displays a square having a side of n = 6 asterisks. For this representation, 28 asterisks and 8 dots were required. * * * * * * * * . . * * * . * * . * * . * * . * * * . . * * * * * * * * Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "For n = 5, precisely 22 asterisks and 4 dots  are required ."
            },
            {
                "B": "For n = 7, precisely 34 asterisks and 15 dots  are required ."
            },
            {
                "C": "For n = 7, precisely 33 asterisks and 16 dots  are required ."
            },
            {
                "D": "For n = 18, precisely 100 asterisks and 224 dots  are required ."
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "CD",
        "index": 17
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm ceFace(T, n, e) , having as a parameter an array T of n natural numbers in ascending order ( T[1], T[2], …, T[n]) and natural numbers n and e (1 ≤ n, e ≤ 10000).     Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm returns 0 if number e does not belong to the array T."
            },
            {
                "B": "If the number e is odd and belongs to the array T, the algorithm returns the index of e in T using the\nbinary search algorithm."
            },
            {
                "C": "If the number e is odd and belongs to the array T, the algorithm returns the index of e in T using the\nsequential search algorithm."
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm returns the index of e in T."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm ceFace(T,  n, e):\n    If e MOD 2 = 0 then\n        a ← 1\n        b ← n\n        While a ≤ b execute\n            m ← (a + b) DIV 2\n            If e < T[m] then\n                b ← m - 1\n            else\n                If e > T[m] then\n                    a ← m + 1\n                else\n                    return m\n                EndIf\n            EndIf\n        EndWhile\n        return 0\n    else\n        c ← 1\n        g ← 0\n        While (c ≤ n) AND (g = 0) execute\n            If e = T[c] then\n                g = c\n            EndIf\n            c ← c + 1\n        EndWhile\n        return g\n    EndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "AC",
        "index": 18
    },
    {
        "question": " 19. Let us consider the algorithm calcul(x, n) , where the input parameters are the natural numbers n and x (1 ≤ x ≤ n < 10). Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "If n = 5 and x = 2, the algorithm returns 20."
            },
            {
                "B": "If n = 3 and x = 2, the algorithm returns  5."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm returns the cardinality of the set { 𝑐1𝑐2…𝑐𝑥  : ci ≠ cj ∀ 1 ≤ i, j ≤ x, i ≠ j, 1 ≤ ci ≤ n}"
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm always returns a value strictly gr eater then 0."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm calcul(x, n):\nb ← 1\nFor i ← 1, n - x execute\nb ← b + i\nEndFor\na ← b\nFor i ← n – x + 1, n execute\na ← a + i\nEndFor\nreturn a - b\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "BD",
        "index": 19
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm s(a, b, c),  where a, b, c are positive natural numbers (1 ≤ a, b, c ≤ 10000). ",
        "answers": [],
        "code": "Algorithm s(a, b, c):\n    If (a = 1) OR (b = 1) OR (c = 1) then\n        return 1\n    else\n        If a > b then\n            return a * s(a - 1, b, c)\n         else\n             If a < b then\n                return b * s(a, b - 1, c)\n            else\n                return c * s(a - 1, b - 1, c - 1)\n            EndIf\n        EndIf\n    EndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "AC",
        "index": 20
    },
    {
        "question": "20a. Which of the following statements are true when  a = b and a < c? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm computes and returns c! / (c - a)!"
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm computes and returns  c! / (c – a + 1)!"
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm computes and returns  c! / (c – a - 1)!"
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm computes and returns the number of combinations of c taken (a - 1) at a time"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "AD",
        "index": 21
    },
    {
        "question": "20b. Given  a = 3, b = 4, c = 7, the algorit hm returns : ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "224"
            },
            {
                "B": "56"
            },
            {
                "C": "336"
            },
            {
                "D": "168"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "A",
        "index": 22
    },
    {
        "question": " Let us consider the algorithm  numere(a, b, c, d, e) , which receive s as input parameters five integer numbers  a, b, c, d and e (1 ≤ a, b ≤ 10000, 2 ≤ c ≤ 16, 1 ≤ d < c). Which of the following statements are true  when  calling numere(a, b, c, d, 0) ? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm returns True  if the representations in base c of the numbers a and b contain the\ndigit d occurring an equal number of times and False  otherwise"
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm  returns True if digit d occurs  in the base c representation of the number a and in\nthe base c representation of the number b, False  otherwise"
            },
            {
                "C": "Calling numere(a, b, c, d, 0)  returns the same value as when calling numere(b, a, c, d, 0)"
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm  returns True if the digit d occurs on the same positions in the base c representation\nof the numbers a and b and False otherwise"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm numere(a, b, c, d, e):\nIf a = 0 AND b = 0 then\nIf e = 0 then\nreturn True\nelse\nreturn False\nEndIf\nEndIf\nIf a MOD c = d then\ne = e + 1\nEndIf\nIf b MOD c = d then\ne = e – 1\nEndIf\nreturn numere(a DIV c, b DIV c, c, d, e)\nEndAlgorithm",
        "correct_answers": "A",
        "index": 23
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the array s of natural numbers where: si = {𝑥,                       if 𝑖=1 𝑥+1,               if 𝑖=2 𝑠(𝑖−1)@𝑠(𝑖−2)  if 𝑖>2   , (i = 1, 2, ...). The operator @ concatenates the digits from the left and right operands, in this order (the digits of base 10 representation), and x is a natural number (1 ≤ x ≤ 99). For example, if x = 3, the array s is 3, 4, 43, 434, 43443, ... . For a na tural number k (1 ≤ k ≤ 30) state the number of digits of the item in  s that precedes the item having  k1 digits, where k1 is the lowest number where k ≤ k1 ≤ 30 and there exists an item having k1 digits. ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "for x = 15 and k = 8, the number of digits of the desired item is 6."
            },
            {
                "B": "for x = 2 și k = 6, the number of digits of the desired item is 6."
            },
            {
                "C": "for x = 14 și k = 27, the number of digits of the desired item is 26."
            },
            {
                "D": "for x = 5 și k = 12, the number of digits of the desired item is 8."
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "correct_answers": "C",
        "index": 24
    },
    {
        "question": " Let us consider the following  recursive algorithm  fibonacci(n) , where n is a natural number (1 ≤ n ≤ 100).   Determine  the number of times that  the message  “Aici” is displayed for a call of  fibonacci(n ). ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "fibonacci(n)  number of times ."
            },
            {
                "B": "fibonacci(n -1) number of times."
            },
            {
                "C": "fibonacci(n) -1 number of times."
            },
            {
                "D": "fibonacci(n) - fibonacci(n -1) number of times."
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm fibonacci(n):\n    If n ≤ 1 then\n        Write \"Aici\"\n        return 1\n    else\n        return fibonacci(n  - 1) + fibonacci(n  - 2)\n    EndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "index": 25
    },
    {
        "question": " 24.   Consider the expression : E(x) = a0 + a 1*x + a2*x2 + a3*x3 + a4*x4, where a0, a1, a2, a3, a4 and x are non-zero real numbers . The minimum number of multiplications needed to compute the value of the expression E(x) is: ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "4"
            },
            {
                "B": "5"
            },
            {
                "C": "7"
            },
            {
                "D": "3"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "index": 26
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm  f(x, n)  where x, n are natural numbers and x > 0. ",
        "answers": [],
        "code": "Algorithm f(x, n):\n2.      If n = 0 then\n3.          return 1\n4.      EndIf\n5.      m ← n DIV 2\n6.      p ← f(x, m)\n7.      If n MOD 2 = 0 then\n8.          return p * p\n9.      EndIf\n10.     return x * p * p\nEndAlgorithm",
        "index": 27
    },
    {
        "question": "25a. Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm returns xn running approximately n recursive calls."
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm returns xn making  approximately log 2 n recursive calls."
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm returns xn if and only if n is a power of 2"
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm returns xn if and only if n is even."
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "index": 28
    },
    {
        "question": "25b. Let us consider line 10 replaced with: 10.     return x * f(x, n – 1) Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "The algorithm does not return xn anymore"
            },
            {
                "B": "The algorithm returns xn+1"
            },
            {
                "C": "The algorithm runs approximately n2 recursive calls."
            },
            {
                "D": "The algorithm returns xn"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "index": 29
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm f2(a,b)  having parameters a and b natural numbers, and the algorithm f(arr, i, n, p)  having as parameters the array arr with n integers ( arr[1], arr[2], …, arr[n]), and the integers i and p. Algorithm f(arr, i, n, p): If i = n then return 0 EndIf n1 ← f(arr, i + 1, n, p) n2 ← 0 If p + 1 ≠ i then n2 ← f(arr, i + 1, n, i) + arr[i] EndIf return f2(n1, n2) EndAlgorithm State which is the result of calling f(arr, 1, 9, -10), if the array arr has the values (10, 1, 5, 4, 7, 12, 1, 12, 6). ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "24"
            },
            {
                "B": "37"
            },
            {
                "C": "39"
            },
            {
                "D": "56"
            }
        ],
        "code": "Algorithm f2(a, b):\n    If a > b then\n        return a\n    else\n        return b\n    EndIf\nEndAlgorithm",
        "index": 30
    },
    {
        "question": "Let us consider the algorithm f(n), having as a parameter the nonzero natural number n which returns a natural number . ",
        "answers": [],
        "code": "Algorithm f(n):\n j ← n\n While j > 1 execute\n  i ← 1\n  While i ≤ n4 execute\n   i ← 4 * i\n   Write \"*\"\n  EndWhile\n  If j DIV 2 > 1 then\n   Write \" \"\n  EndIf\n  j ← j DIV 2\n EndWhile\n return j\nEndAlgorithm",
        "index": 31
    },
    {
        "question": "27a. The time complexity of the algorithm belongs to which of the following complexity class es? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "O(log 2 n)"
            },
            {
                "B": "O(log 22 𝒏)"
            },
            {
                "C": "O(log 42 𝒏)"
            },
            {
                "D": "O(log 2 log 4 n)"
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "index": 32
    },
    {
        "question": "27b. Which of the following statements are true? ",
        "answers": [
            {
                "A": "If n = 10, the algorithm displays groups of 7 asterisks, groups being separated by a space."
            },
            {
                "B": "If n = 20, the algorithm displays  4 groups of asterisks  and 4 space characters."
            },
            {
                "C": "If n = 25, the algorithm displays  48 asterisks , and after each group displays one spac e."
            },
            {
                "D": "If n = 100, the algorithm displays  84 asterisks and  5 space characters."
            }
        ],
        "code": "",
        "index": 33
    }
]